Guide to the Adams T. Rice papers 1922-1960
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Adams T. Rice papers
1922-1960
C0238
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
2 linear feet (3 boxes)
The Adams T. Rice papers consists of newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, photographs, and programs relating to theatre in Detroit, Michigan, the Federal Theatre Project, and Rice's lecture "The Magic of Science." Material was collected by Rice and dates from the 1920s to 1960, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1920s to the 1930s.
Rice, Adams T., 1892-
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Adams T. Rice's daughter Olivia Hudson on October 11, 1979.
Biographical note
Adams T. Rice was born in 1892 in Newton, Massachusetts. He graduated from Newton Technical High School and received his PhD from Brown University in 1915. He also attended classes at the Rhode Island School of Design and the Boston Museum School of Design and completed a certificate in Engineering at Pratt Institute.
In the early 1920s Rice married the actress Helen Elizabeth Morrow. Rice and Morrow worked together at the Bonstelle Stock Company in Detroit, Michigan. In total Rice worked for 18 years with the Bonstelle Stock Companies (Detroit Civic Theatre) as a Stage Manager, Technical Director, and Stage Director. Throughout his career in the theatre he held jobs as Stage Manager for the Northampton Players, The Copley Players in Boston, and Director for the Clair Tree Major Players. He was both owner and director of "The Detroit Players" a traveling dramatic tent show, and spent five summers with various circuses as Lot Superintendent and Transportation Manager. He created the traveling lecture "The Magic of Science" and performed it on the east coast from New York to Boston. Later in his career he was the Director of Video Effects for the Bunin Motion Picture Studio, and created video effects for the Lucky Pup TV program. He also spent time teaching, working as an electrical engineer, designing exhibits for the N.Y. Worlds Fair, and wrote several children's plays.
Scope and Content
The Adams T. Rice papers consists of newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, photographs, and programs relating to theatre in Detroit, Michigan, the Federal Theatre Project, and Rice's lecture "The Magic of Science." Material was collected by Rice and dates from the 1920s to 1960, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1920s to the 1930s.
Material related to the Federal Theatre Project includes newspaper clippings and programs for the productions: American Holiday, Class of '29, Ethiopia, A Hero is Born, It Can't Happen Here, Murder in the Cathedral, and the Sun and I. Also related to the Federal Theatre Project is the publication Red Spotlight, the WPA Federal Theatre Unit Communist Party newsletter. The scrapbooks document the Rice's work with the Bonstelle Company, the Detroit Players, and the Federal Theatre Project.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Related Material
The Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, the Federal Theatre Project collection, the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, as well as numerous other personal papers.
Index Terms
Persons:
Bonstelle, Jessie.; Rice, Adams T., 1892-
Corporate Names:
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
Actors--Photographs.; New Deal, 1933-1939.; Performing arts.; Theater--United States.
Document Types:
Scrapbooks.
Contents List
- Bonstelle Playhouse, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Programs and photocopies of newspaper clippings
- Detroit Civic Theatre letterhead; Helen Morrow membership card, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Federal Theatre Project: American Holiday newsclippings, February 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Federal Theatre Project: Class of '29 newsclippings, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Federal Theatre Project: Ethiopia newsclipping, circa 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Federal Theatre Project: A Hero is Born, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Federal Theatre Project: Highlights of the First Production Conference in New York City, July 22-24, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Federal Theatre Project: It Can't Happen Here newsclippings, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Federal Theatre Project: Murder in the Cathedral newsclippings, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Federal Theatre Project: Playbills, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Federal Theatre Project: Red Spotlight, May 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  WPA Federal Theatre Unit Communist Party newsletter
- Federal Theatre Project: The Sun and I newsclippings, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Magic of Science, circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Photographs and program for lecture
- Newsclippings, 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Newsclippings, circa 1927 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Newsclippings, circa 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Newsclippings, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Newsclippings, June 13, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Newsclippings: Ann Harding, October 21, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Newsclippings: The Barretts of Wimpale Street, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Newsclippings: Detroit Players tent show, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Newsclippings: The Goose Hangs High, The Magic Cloak, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Newsclippings: 'Let's Feed Our Own' slogan of dinner club for actors, February 1, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Newsclippings: New York Herald Tribune, April 22, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Newsclippings: Saint Joan, April 3, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Newsclippings: The Water Babies, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Newsclippings and programs, 1928-1960 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Newsclippings, programs, memos, 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Photographs, 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Theatre production photographs, portraits, Helen Morrow
- Resume, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Scrapbook: Bonstelle Company, 1925-1929 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Scrapbook: Bonstelle Playhouse, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Scrapbook of newsclippings (1 of 2), 1922-1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook of newsclippings (2 of 2), 1922-1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook of newsclippings covers, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook, 1928-1930 (Box 3)
  Newspaper clippings about the Detroit Players.
- Scrapbook, 1930 (Box 3)
  Dr. Charlotte Richmond, The Detroit Players publicity. Includes newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and handwritten notes.